{"description":"Default","name":"Inference for Categorical Data: Proportions","questions":[{"correct":3,"image_data":[],"options":["σ ","p̂ ","x̄ ","p"],"question":"What is the correct variable for population proportions?"},{"correct":0,"image_data":[],"options":["Ho: pM1 = pM2\nHa: pM1 < pM2","Ho: pM1 = pM2\nHa: pM1 ≠ pM2","Ho: pM1 ≠ pM2 \nHa: pM1 > pM2","Ho: pM1 = pM2\nHa: pM1 > pM2"],"question":"An internet service provider conducts a survey every month to determine the proportion of homeowners using their high-speed internet. The service provider predicts that the proportion of homeowners who use their high-speed internet increases. Which of the following are appropriate hypotheses for the test?\n"},{"correct":2,"image_data":[],"options":["Point Estimate, Sampling variability ","Point Estimate, population parameter","Statistic, population parameter","Critical value, confidence level"],"question":"Fill in the blanks. Using a ___ this is used to estimate the  ____."},{"correct":3,"image_data":[],"options":["1.01","1.18","1.51","1.81"],"question":"Which of the following shows the critical value for an 93% confidence interval."},{"correct":2,"image_data":[],"options":["With 90% confidence the true proportion of people who own an iPhone is between 0.66 and 0.80","With 90% confidence the true proportion of people who own an iPhone is between 0.67 and 0.79","With 90% confidence the true proportion of people who own an iPhone is between 0.73 and 0.80","With 90% confidence the true proportion of people who own an iPhone is between 0.26 and 0.8"],"question":" simple random sample was conducted to find how many people have an iPhone. Out of 128 people it was discovered that 94 people use an iPhone. What is the true proportion of people who own an iPhone with 90% confidence interval."},{"correct":3,"image_data":[],"options":["(-0.20, 0.05)","(-0.22, 0.07) ","(-0.25, 0.11)","(-0.27, 0.13) "],"question":"A study is conducted on which local theater provides the best shows. From Crescent Moon theatre 53 out of the 92 audience were satisfied with the shows performed. From the Mirage Theatre 46 out of the 71 audience were satisfied with the shows performed. Which of the following shows the true difference in population proportions between audiences from Crescent and Mirage theatre with 99% confidence? "},{"correct":0,"image_data":[],"options":["I. only","II. only","I. and III. ","II. and III. "],"question":"Which of the following is NOT true about p-values?\nI. Small p-values indicate evidence against the alternate hypothesis.\nII. Large p-values indicate evidence to fail against the null hypothesis.\nIII. P-value less than the significance level gives strong evidence to reject the null hypothesis."},{"correct":1,"image_data":[],"options":["To increase power in a statistical test, decrease the significance level.","Power represents a probability of accepting the null hypothesis.","Powr and Type II error are inversely related.","The only factor that affects power is sample size."],"question":"Which of the following is true about power?"},{"correct":0,"image_data":[],"options":["310","315","380","385"],"question":"Suppose a parent wants to estimate the true proportion of parents who have kids who play more than one sport. If the parent wants to find with 95% confidence and a margin of error of no more than 0.03, which of the following is the smallest sample size possible?"},{"correct":1,"image_data":[],"options":["Yes, since the p-value is less than 0.05 indicating that there is convincing evidence to support the survey claim that more than 45% of people like Pepsi better than Coca Cola.","Yes, since the p-value is greater than 0.05, indicating that there is convincing evidence to support the survey claim that more than 45% of people like Pepsi better than Coca Cola.","No, since the p-value is greater than 0.05, indicating that there is not enough evidence to support the survey claim that more than 45% of people like Pepsi better than Coca Cola.","No, since the p-value is less than 0.05, indicating that there is not enough evidence to support the survey claim that more than 45% of people like Pepsi better than Coca Cola."],"question":"In a survey more than 45% claims to like Pepsi better than Coca Cola. The researcher conducted a study and out of 125 randomly sampled people 60 people liked Pepsi better than Coca Cola. Is there enough evidence to support the survey at a 0.05 significance level?"}],"time_created":1686582443.681}